Guide to the Francis Francois papers, 1967-2004
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives.
George Mason University Francis Francois collection
1980-2004
1967-2004
C0245
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives.
15.5 linear feet (32 boxes)
Transportation-related papers, books, and audiotapes that document Francois' time with the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials.
Francois, Francis B.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Marie Francois in 2013.
Biographical Information
Francis B. "Frank" Francois was born in 1934 in Barnum, Iowa. He attended Iowa State University, where he earned a B.S. in engineering, and the George Washington University, where he earned a law degree. Francois worked as a patent attorney, and he served as County Commissioner of Prince George's County, Maryland from 1966-1971 and as a County Councilman from 1971 to 1980. In 1980, Francois became the Executive Director of the Association of American State Highway and Transportation Officials (AASHTO). He was also affiliated with a number of other transportation-related organizations, including the National Steering Committee on Transportation Operations, the Transportation Research Board, and the Intelligent Transportation Society of America. Francois retired from AASHTO in 1999, after which he served as a private consultant.
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection documents Frank Francois's role as Executive Director of the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials (AASHTO) through transportation-related correspondence, meeting and conference records, reports, publications, and audiotapes. A small amount of realia, as well as a VHS tape, CD, and floppy disks, are also included. The majority of materials date from 1980-1999, while Francois was with AASHTO. A few reports, brochures, and other publications date from Francois's years as an elected official in Prince George's County, Maryland (1962-1980) or from his time as a private consultant (1999-2004).
Series 1: Correspondence (1980-2004) includes letters, memos, and print-outs of email correspondence, both internal within AASHTO and with members of other organizations. A few letters related to family and personal matters are included as well.
Series 2: Meetings, events, and committees (1975-2004) includes agendas, minutes, notes, informational packets, papers, and correspondence from various meetings, conferences, and other events attended by Francois as a participant or speaker.
Series 3: Research and reports (1967-2004) includes research papers, reports, surveys, and other educational materials produced by AASHTO, the Transportation Research Board (TRB), and other transportation-related organizations.
Series 4: Subject files (1980-2000) includes folders whose materials relate to the same subject, such as Francois's retirement from AASHTO, AASHTO's Board of Directors, and other AASHTO-related personnel documents, as well as the International Road Federation.
Series 5: Publications (1968-2004) includes brochures, pamphlets, directories, internal newsletters, handbooks, published reports, and other materials produced by the US Department of Transportation, state departments of transportation, AASHTO, the Transportation Research Board, and other organizations.
Series 6: Audiovisual materials and realia (1988-1997) includes items such as an AASHTO calculator and desktop road sign, as well as a CD, VHS tape, and 40 audio cassette tapes from the Transportation Research Board's annual meeting and other organizational meetings.
Arrangement
The collection is organized alphabetically within seven series based on subject and format:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1980-2004 (Boxes 1-2)
Series 2: Meetings, events, and committees, 1975-2004 (Boxes 3-10)
Series 3: Research and reports, 1967-2004 (Boxes 11-22)
Series 4: Subject files, 1980-2000 (Boxes 23-25)
Series 5: Publications, 1968-2004 (Boxes 25-30)
Series 6: Audiovisual materials and realia, 1988-1997 (Boxes 31-32)
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds many other collections on transportation history and planning.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Index Terms
Persons:
Francois, Francis B.
Corporate Names:
American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials.
Subjects:
Transportation--United States--Planning.
Document Types:
Sound recordings.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1980-2004; (2 boxes)
  This series includes letters, memos, and print-outs of email correspondence, both internal within AASHTO and with members of other organizations. A few letters related to family and personal matters are included as well.
  - AASHTO Requests for biographical reports, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Staff Reorganization and meeting agenda, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Society for Testing Materials and AASHTO correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Compilation of appreciation letters for Francois retirement, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Forwarded jokes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Francois letter to Steny Hoyer, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Francois's retirement from AASHTO, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Howe, Anderson and Steyer P.C. and list of AASHTO employees, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Infrastructure renewal working group correspondence, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mary Peters correspondence, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memos from State Departments of Transportation, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - National Center for Asphalt Technology, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - National Highway system origins, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Research Council correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notes, Congress updates, Steering Committee roster, meeting agenda, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notes and letters associated with Francois position as director, AASHTO meeting schedule, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Personal correspondence regarding daughter, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Statements, interviews, and correspondence, associated notes and articles, 1978-1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Teleconference summary, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Transportation Indicators Workshop preparation and notes from Economic indicators conference call, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - TRB email correspondence, Where the Weather Meets the Road, and reports, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - TRB History Meetings and correspondence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - World Interchange Network correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series 2: Meetings, events, and committees, 1975-2004; (8 boxes)
  This series includes agendas, minutes, notes, informational packets, papers, and correspondence from various meetings, conferences, and other events attended by Francois as a participant or speaker.
  - 2000 AASHTO Washington Briefing (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Annual conference program, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Annual Meeting (pt 1 of 3), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Annual Meeting (pt 2 of 3), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO Annual Meeting (pt 3 of 3), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Board of Directors and Committees, FHWA pamphlet, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AASHTO Executive Committee Agendas, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - AASHTO Executive Committee Agendas, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - AASHTO Executive Committee Agendas, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - AASHTO Executive Committee Meetings, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Governing Documents, Executive Director description, and annual meeting guidelines, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Meeting workbook, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Special Committee on International Activity (pt 1 of 2), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO Special Committee on International Activity (pt 2 of 2), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Standing Committee on Research, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - AASHTO Strategic Planning Conference (pt 1 of 2), 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - AASHTO Strategic Planning Conference (pt 2 of 2), 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - AASHTO Strategic Plan, TEA-21, and meetings, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO- TRB Meeting, Boothbay Harbor, ME, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Washington Briefing, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - APWA, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors National Association of Counties (pt 1 of 3), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors National Association of Counties (pt 2 of 3), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors National Association of Counties (pt 3 of 3), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CATT Board Meeting, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Committee for Study of a Future Strategic Highway Research Program, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Committee for Study of a Future Strategic Highway Research Program and Workshop on Pavement Renewal for Urban freeways, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Conference on the Future of Federalism, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Conference on Transportation Issues in Large US Cities, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - CUTC presentation, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ENO, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Highway Subcommittee on Materials, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ICMA Conference Notes, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Infrastructure Renewal Working Group, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - International Organizations involved in the Road Sector, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - International Symposium on Transportation technology transfer, assorted International transportation conference and committee documents, 2000-2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - ITE Spring Conference, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - ITS/Equals 3, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ITS Meeting, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - ITS presentation transparencies, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - ITS Public Safety Meeting, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Meetings about Public Transportation, 1996, 1997, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - National Conference on Federalism in Action, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Dialogue on Operations, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - National Steering Committee Agendas for Meetings, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - National Steering Committee Meetings, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - National Steering Committee Transportation Operations meeting, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - National Steering Committee on Transportation Operations (pt 1 of 2), 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - National Steering Committee on Transportation Operations (pt 2 of 2), 2001 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - National Training Steering Committee Conferences, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - National Transportation Management Conferences, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - NCHRP project, 1998-2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "No Name" Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Notes on history of state highways, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Overhead transparencies for highway funding presentations, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Project calendar for FBF, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Publishing Task Force, 1997-2001 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - R+T Working Group Meeting, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Regents Lecture at UC Berkeley, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Regional Dialog Sessions, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Research and Technology Coordinating Committee Symposium, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Research and Technology Working Group, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Resume, Cover letter, notes, correspondence regarding Francois's hiring as Executive Director of AASHTO, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Retirement Dinner for Francois at Transportation Research Board Meeting, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Strategic Highway Research Program, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Surface Transportation Environmental Research Advisory Board, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Task Force on Private Sector Abroad, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Text and articles for presentations, 1985-1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Text and articles for presentations, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Text for presentations, 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Transportation Research Board (pt 1 of 2), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Transportation Research Board (pt 2 of 2), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Transportation Research Board meeting, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Transportation Research Board History Committee, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Transportation Research Board Symposium, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - TRB Annual Meeting, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - TRB Committee Chairs Information, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - TRB Distinguished Lecture, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - TRB Luncheon Address, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - TRB/SCOR Meetings and Workshop, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - TRB Study for a Future Strategic Highway Research Program Committee Meeting, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Transportation- Some thoughts on yesterday, today, and tomorrow, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - World Bank meeting on technical aid, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Series 3: Research and reports, 1967-2004; (12 boxes)
  This series includes research papers, reports, surveys, and other educational materials produced by AASHTO, the Transportation Research Board (TRB), and other transportation-related organizations.
  - 1997 Statistical Summaries: FTA Grant Assistance Programs (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Activities and Policies, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Administrative Resolutions, 1985-1999 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Annual Report of Activities, 1981-1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO Annual Report of Activities, 1991-1999 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Budget Report and outside review, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - AASHTO Budget, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - AASHTO - The Changing State DOT and International Agenda, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Committee Research and Reports, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Documents, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Joint position statements and reports, Francois correspondence as consultant, CD, and brochures, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO planning, remarks, surveys, 1986-1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Proposed budget for FY 1989, Better Roads, 1988, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Reauthorization reports, 1995, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Reauthorization steering committee, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO related plans and reports, correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO reorganization draft, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Research, reports, surveys, etc., 1994-1997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO, State DOT, and US DOT reports, 1986-1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Strategic Plan and operational plan/work program, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO Strategic Plan, various other reports on national and international transportation, 1994-1998 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO trademark registrations, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO transportation policy book, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO and Urban Mobility Corporation internal publications, 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO, US DOT, and Transportation Research Board reports and pamphlets, New Zealand Ministry of Transport report, 1983-1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO, various brochures, agendas, and reports, 1991-1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Annual report of AASHTO activities, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - ARTBA proposed sanctions, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Beyond Gridlock report, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - California Department of Transportation - Transportation Management Baseline Inventory, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Conservatives and Mass Transit, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Digest of State Transit and Programs, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Directory, Pan-American Institute of Highways, National Cooperative Highway/research program report, 1991-1999 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Engineering Education pamphlets and reports, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago staff memoranda reports on public expenditure, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Francois biographical article, economic and transit reports, 1973-1976, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Gas tax reports and correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Gas tax reports, press releases, others, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Greater Washington Area Research Center, Maryland Highways master plan, other proceedings and reports, 1967-2004 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Highway safety strategic plan, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Impact on states due to delay in reauthorization, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Intelligent Vehicle Highway Systems, Intelligent Transportation Society (pt 1 of 2), 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Intelligent Vehicle Highway Systems, Intelligent Transportation Society (pt 2 of 2), 1992-1997 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Interjurisdictional Tax and Policy Competition: Good or Bad for the Federal System?, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - International Road Federation survey and response, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - International Road Foundation and World Bank reports, data, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - NAE workshop on transportation indicators, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The National Academies Weather Research for Surface Transportation: The Roadway Environment, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - National Highway System reports, brochures, news, etc., 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - National Transportation Product Evaluation ballots and associated material, 1993-1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets, steering committee comments, 10-year-plan news article, 1982-2001 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Papers from National Steering Committee on Transportation Operations meeting, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Proposed Legislative Language for the Reauthorization of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Report on the 1992 US tour of European concrete highways (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Report on MagLev transportation to Maryland General Assembly, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Reports and publications, Maryland highway map, 1996-1998, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Reports, trade journals, and speeches by Francois, 1995-2004 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Reports from the Transportation Research Board National Research Council (pt 1 of 2), 1984-1999 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Reports from the Transportation Research Board National Research Council (pt 2 of 2), 1984-1999 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Research material, reports, profiles, AASHTO lists, committee information, 1998-1999 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Research on AASHTO's effectiveness, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Road To Ruin, ARTBA anniversary letter, History of Load Factor rating, Nebraska, 1995-2001 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Rural and Specialized Transportation, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Strategic Planning for National Highway System, Standing Committee on Highways, others, 1991-1993 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Study for a Future Strategic Highway Research Program, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Survey on the Impacts of Failing to Renew ISTEA before October 1, 1997: an AASHTO report, August 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Survey of State Capital funding for public transportation, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Survey of state involvement in public transportation (pt 1 of 2), 1980s (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Survey of state involvement in public transportation (pt 2 of 2), 1980s (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Survey of state involvement in public transportation, 1990s (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Transportation for a Competitive America, 1998-2002 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Transportation 2020 (pt 1 of 2), 1988-1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Transportation 2020 (pt 2 of 2), 1988-1990 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Transportation 2020 alliance building manual, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Transportation Research Board, Maryland DOT, and US DOT reports, CD, 1999-2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Transportation management policy reports and press releases, 1992-1997 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Transportation Research Board Measuring State Transportation Program performance, Transportation Performance Indicators, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Transportation Research Board Strategic Approach to Transportation Security: Advice to the TSA, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Transportation Research Board Study for a Future Strategic Highway Research program, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Transportation Solutions Group reports on Suburban Maryland (pt 1 of 2), 1999 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Transportation Solutions Group reports on Suburban Maryland (pt 2 of 2), 1999 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - UNC-Charlotte transportation report and response, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Urban transportation planning in the United States, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Workshop and committee agendas, correspondence, reports, brochures, 1991-2003 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - World Bank - Working group on international framework for key data related to roads, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Series 4: Subject files, 1980-2000; (3 boxes)
  This series includes folders whose materials relate to the same subject, such as Francois's retirement from AASHTO, AASHTO's Board of Directors, and other AASHTO-related personnel documents, as well as the International Road Federation.
  - AASHTO Administrative Documents, 1992-1998 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO appointments, retirement, travel, 1998-1999 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Board of Directors, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Committee Officer Appointments, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO Contacts, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Executive Director transition documents, 1980, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - AASHTO files, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - AASHTO Handbook (pt 1 of 4), 1979-1997 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - AASHTO Handbook (pt 2 of 4), 1979-1997 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Handbook (pt 3 of 4), 1979-1997 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Handbook (pt 4 of 4), 1979-1997 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO and TRB program to honor Francois, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Asset Management, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Asset Management, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Background of Transportation at time of Francois hiring, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Documents relating to Francois retirement, Public Works magazine, IVHS America comments, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Employee bios, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Executive Director position hiring info, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Floppy disks, 1997-1998 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Francois biography, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Francois resume and acceptance of Executive Director title, AASHTO information/policies, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Francois retirement, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Francois's Role as Executive Director of AASHTO, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - International Delegation Planning, 1996-1997 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - International Road Federation notes, email, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Recruitment for Executive Director position, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Surface Transportation Policy Project Newsletters and releases, AASHTO response, 1994-1996 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Series 5: Publications, 1968-2004; (6 boxes)
  This series includes brochures, pamphlets, directories, internal newsletters, handbooks, published reports, and other materials produced by the US Department of Transportation, state departments of transportation, AASHTO, the Transportation Research Board, and other organizations.
  - AASHTO Employment and Salary Administration Policy, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - AASHTO's Governing Documents, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - AASHTO's Governing Documents, 1992-1998 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - AASHTO Guide to Recruitment and Retention of Civil Engineers, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - AASHTO Publications catalog, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - AASHTO Quarterly, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - AASHTO Reference Books (pt 1 of 5), 1980-1983 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - AASHTO Reference Books (pt 2 of 5), 1984-1986 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - AASHTO Reference Books (pt 3 of 5), 1986-1991 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - AASHTO Reference Books (pt 4 of 5), 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - AASHTO Reference Books (pt 5 of 5), 1994-1998 (Box 27, Folder 1)